<mediawiki xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.8/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.8/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.8.xsd" version="0.8" xml:lang="en">
  <siteinfo>
    <sitename>Wikipedia</sitename>
    <base>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page</base>
    <generator>MediaWiki 1.24wmf12</generator>
    <case>first-letter</case>
    <namespaces>
      <namespace key="-2" case="first-letter">Media</namespace>
      <namespace key="-1" case="first-letter">Special</namespace>
      <namespace key="0" case="first-letter" />
      <namespace key="1" case="first-letter">Talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="2" case="first-letter">User</namespace>
      <namespace key="3" case="first-letter">User talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="4" case="first-letter">Wikipedia</namespace>
      <namespace key="5" case="first-letter">Wikipedia talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="6" case="first-letter">File</namespace>
      <namespace key="7" case="first-letter">File talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="8" case="first-letter">MediaWiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="9" case="first-letter">MediaWiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="10" case="first-letter">Template</namespace>
      <namespace key="11" case="first-letter">Template talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="12" case="first-letter">Help</namespace>
      <namespace key="13" case="first-letter">Help talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="14" case="first-letter">Category</namespace>
      <namespace key="15" case="first-letter">Category talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="100" case="first-letter">Portal</namespace>
      <namespace key="101" case="first-letter">Portal talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="108" case="first-letter">Book</namespace>
      <namespace key="109" case="first-letter">Book talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="118" case="first-letter">Draft</namespace>
      <namespace key="119" case="first-letter">Draft talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="446" case="first-letter">Education Program</namespace>
      <namespace key="447" case="first-letter">Education Program talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="710" case="first-letter">TimedText</namespace>
      <namespace key="711" case="first-letter">TimedText talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="828" case="first-letter">Module</namespace>
      <namespace key="829" case="first-letter">Module talk</namespace>
    </namespaces>
  </siteinfo>
  <page>
    <title>Loppers</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>4543571</id>
    <revision>
      <id>612164842</id>
      <parentid>585928646</parentid>
      <timestamp>2014-06-09T04:03:04Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Plastikspork</username>
        <id>5075409</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Split per TfD</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="3218">{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
[[Image:Astschere.jpg|thumb|Bypass loppers with double curved blades]]

'''Loppers''' are a type of [[scissors]] used for [[pruning]] twigs and small branches, like secateurs with very long handles. They are the largest type of manual garden cutting tool. They are usually operated with two hands, and with handles typically between {{convert|30|cm|in}} &amp; {{convert|91|cm|in}} long to give good leverage. Some have telescopic handles which can be extended to a length of two metres, in order to increase leverage and to reach high branches on a tree.

The word ''lopper'' can be used in the singular or the plural, with precisely the same meaning. The plural form, most common in speech but less so in print, seems to be on the model of a ''pair of scissors''. The name of the tool is derived from the verb &quot;to lop&quot;, meaning to cut branches or twigs, which in turn derives from the noun of precisely the same form: a &quot;lop&quot; is a period or session of branch cutting. The noun and verb first appeared in [[Middle English]], but have no known antecedents or cognates in other languages.

The main distinction among loppers is between ''bypass'' and ''anvil'' types. Bypass loppers operate like scissors, except that they generally only have one blade that moves past a jaw or hook that has an approximately square edge that is not typically sharpened and is usually concave or hook shaped in order keep branches from slipping out of the jaws. The jaws of bypass loppers may be straight, curved, or one curved with one straight. Anvil loppers have a single sharpened blade, with a straight or sometimes curved edge, that closes against a similarly contoured flat anvil like surface on the other side of the jaws, usually made of a softer metal than the blade.

Anvil loppers have the disadvantage of tending to crush rather than cut, sometimes leaving an untidy wound, more vulnerable to infection. Their main advantages are of relative strength and of being less likely to jam with fibrous material. Very hard or resilient branches can sometimes deflect a bypass lopper so that material either binds between the blades or even levers them apart, which can be dangerous both to the tool and the operator.

Both types of lopper generally have a sprung adjusting screw at the [[Fulcrum (mechanics)|fulcrum]], which can be used to tighten the blades as they loosen in use. With bypass loppers, it is also useful for releasing material jamming the blades. Anvil loppers usually have a screw for adjusting or detaching the plate, so that it can be moved to compensate for wear or replaced entirely.

Loppers are mainly used for the pruning of tree branches with diameters less than {{convert|5|cm|in|sigfig=1}}. Some of the newer lopper designs have a gear or compound lever system which increases the force applied to the blades, or a ratchet drive.

==See also==
*[[Pruning shears]] (secateurs)—smaller garden cutting tools usually operated with one hand

{{Garden tools}}

[[Category:Gardening tools]]
[[Category:Habitat management equipment and methods]]
[[Category:Scissors]]

[[ar:مقصات التشذيب]]
[[bg:Лозарска ножица]]
[[pdc:Baamscheer]]
[[ksh:Boumschėer]]</text>
      <sha1>kk9k38hkhg6mei8madv85srnz5iyuv4</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Clauss Cutlery Company</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>23551370</id>
    <revision>
      <id>609269256</id>
      <parentid>595832274</parentid>
      <timestamp>2014-05-19T18:08:59Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Caea8937</username>
        <id>7735193</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Added latest events to the article</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="9598">{{Infobox company
|name=Clauss
|logo=[[Image:Clauss Logo.gif|200px]]
|industry=Cutting Tools
|owner=[[Acme United Corporation]]
|homepage=[http://www.claussco.com Clauss Home]
}}

'''Clauss Cutlery’s''' long and vivid history started in 1877 when John Clauss and his younger brother Henrie established Elyria Shear Works in [[Elyria, Ohio|Elyria]], [[Ohio]]. At one time the company was the largest manufacturer of [[scissors]] and shears in the [[world]] and was acquired by [[Acme United Corporation]] in 2004.

==History==

===1877 - 1918===
The two brothers John and Henrie Clauss, of [[Germany|German]] origin, started Elyria Shear Works from a one-room [[building]] in Elyria, Ohio.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.rbhayes.org/hayes/mssfind/285/carrollfamily.htm#Biographical%20Sketch1 |title=Carroll Family &gt; Biographical Sketch |publisher=rbhayes.org}} Retrieved on June 28, 2009.&lt;/ref&gt; Together with five [[Employee#Employee|employees]], they began manufacturing scissors, shears, [[straight razor]]s and [[Serrated blade|serrated]] [[kitchen]] [[Knife|knives]].&lt;ref name=&quot;Great Men Of America&quot;&gt;{{cite web|url=http://news.google.com/newspapers?nid=799&amp;dat=19770830&amp;id=_10RAAAAIBAJ&amp;sjid=FYgDAAAAIBAJ&amp;pg=5568,4818587 |title=Great Men Of America |publisher=The Bryan Times}} Retrieved on July 2, 2009.&lt;/ref&gt;

In the early 1880s, with his shear business prospering, John Clauss planned a major [[Economic expansion|expansion]]. In August 1887, he moved the company to [[Fremont, Ohio|Fremont]], Ohio to be near an accessible, abundant supply of [[natural gas]] which had recently been discovered.&lt;ref name=&quot;Great Men Of America&quot;/&gt; The gas was ideally suited to fuel the [[furnace]]s for the company’s [[forge]]s and [[foundry]]. Clauss erected a two [[Storey|stories]] high [[Factory|plant]] at the corner of North Buchanan Street and Pine Street. Within one year, the company was producing 3,000 pairs of shears and scissors a day.&lt;ref name=&quot;Great Men Of America&quot;/&gt;

On January 17, 1889, [[disaster]] struck as the plant was completely destroyed by fire, causing 125 employees to lose their jobs. However, in less than four months, Clauss built a new plant and was back in full operation.&lt;ref name=&quot;Firms aim to regain cutting edge&quot;&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.toledoblade.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20041003/BUSINESS03/410030324 |title=Firms aim to regain cutting edge |publisher=toledoblade.com}} Retrieved on July 1, 2009.&lt;/ref&gt; The new four story [[brick]] building at the corner of State Street and Sandusky Avenue was the largest shear factory in the world at that moment.&lt;ref name=&quot;Firms aim to regain cutting edge&quot;/&gt; Clauss also used this opportunity to change the company’s name to Clauss Shear Company.

===1919 - 1945===

In 1919, Clauss Shear [[Mergers_and_acquisitions#Merger|merged]] with Henkel Company, also from Fremont, Ohio, to create Henkel-Clauss Company.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.rbhayes.org/hayes/mssfind/285/carrollfamily.htm#Biographical%20Sketch1 |title=Carroll Family &gt; Biographical Sketch |publisher=rbhayes.org}} Retrieved on June 28, 2009.&lt;/ref&gt; Henkel Company was founded in 1906 to manufacture [[manicure]] and [[pedicure]] [[Nail file|files]], knives, shears and razors.&lt;ref name=&quot;U. S. Department of the Interior&quot;&gt;{{cite web|url=http://lcweb2.loc.gov/pnp/habshaer/oh/oh0400/oh0469/data/oh0469.pdf |title=Historic American Engineering Record |publisher=U. S. Department of the Interior}} Retrieved on July 4, 2009.&lt;/ref&gt; The Henkel-Clauss merger created a company with over 1,000 employees and had the largest [[payroll]] in the [[United States]] at that time. John Clauss didn’t live long to enjoy that success as he died later that same year.

In the early 1920s the cutlery business faced a serious [[Problem|setback]] as Germany was permitted to [[export]] shears and scissors duty-free to the United States. The idea behind this was to help Germany pay back its [[World War I]] [[debt]]s. As a consequence, German shears were sold at half the price of American made shears.&lt;ref name=&quot;U. S. Department of the Interior&quot;/&gt; Despite the fierce German competition, Fremont counted twenty-five cutlery businesses and was rightfully known as the &quot;Cutlery Center of the World&quot;.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.rbhayes.org/hayes/mssfind/285/carrollfamily.htm#Biographical%20Sketch1 |title=Carroll Family &gt; Biographical Sketch |publisher=rbhayes.org}} Retrieved on June 28, 2009.&lt;/ref&gt;

===1946 - 1966===

After [[World War II]], Clauss was unable to compete with [[Europe]]an firms producing household scissors and other simple products because [[wage]]s were much lower in Europe. As a result, the company had no other choice than to shift its focus to [[Industry|industrial]] scissors. Unfortunately, Clauss continued to struggle as much of its [[Revenue|sales]] were to industries in decline or to businesses where [[automation]] was reducing the need for scissors.&lt;ref name=&quot;Firms aim to regain cutting edge&quot;/&gt;

In 1954 the corporate name was changed to Clauss Cutlery Company to eliminate the confusion with the German cutlery firm [[J.A. Henckels]].

===1967 - 2004===

In 1967 Clauss was taken over by Alco Standard Corporation. Alco Standard, which later divested its manufacturing companies to create Alco Industries Inc., integrated Clauss into its existing structure to manufacture tools for industrial [[niche market]]s. For instance, Clauss made [[Surgery|surgical]] scissors for [[human eye|eye]] operations, heavy duty [[metal]] [[cutting]] shears, [[poultry]] shears for gutting [[chicken]]s and specialty items such as anti-[[acid]], anti-[[magnetic]] [[tweezers]] for the [[electronics]] industry.&lt;ref name=&quot;The Blade&quot;&gt;{{cite web|url=http://news.google.com/newspapers?nid=1350&amp;dat=19860506&amp;id=uXoUAAAAIBAJ&amp;sjid=3AIEAAAAIBAJ&amp;pg=5290,3327123 |title=Clauss Cutlery Carves A Niche In Special Field |publisher=The Blade}} Retrieved on June 30, 2009.&lt;/ref&gt;

Clauss had approximately 100 employees and produced about $18 million in annual revenues in the late 1980s, but [[Profit (accounting)|profits]] continued to decline.&lt;ref name=&quot;The Blade&quot;/&gt; In May 2004, Acme United Corporation acquired the Clauss [[inventory]], [[trademark]]s and [[Brand|brand names]] from Alco Industries for approximately $500,000.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite news|url=http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20040601005688/en/Acme-United-Corporation-Acquires-Clauss-Cutlery-Assets |title=Acme United Corporation Acquires Clauss Cutlery Assets |publisher=Business Wire | date=June 1, 2004}} Retrieved on October 16, 2012.&lt;/ref&gt;

===2005 - Present===

The Clauss business was immediately integrated into Acme United's existing operations. Since then, the number of Clauss products has continued to expand. In 2006 and 2007 sewing shears, [[utility knives]], chef shears, hobby knives and a [[titanium]]-bonded spring-assisted [[pruner]] were brought to market.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://yahoo.brand.edgar-online.com/displayfilinginfo.aspx?FilingID=5794970-9751-16256&amp;type=sect&amp;TabIndex=2&amp;companyid=3656&amp;ppu=%252fDefault.aspx%253fcompanyid%253d3656%2526amp%253bformtypeID%253d7 |title=10-K Acme United 2010 |publisher=edgar-online.com}} Retrieved on April 25, 2011.&lt;/ref&gt;

In 2008, Clauss introduced the SpeedPak utility knife and its replaceable cartridges with 10 titanium [[blade]]s. The SpeedPak works like a normal utility knife, except when the blade is dull the user can simply push a button on the side of the knife, pull out the blade, retract the button, and automatically another blade reloaded out of the cartridge. The SpeedPak won a [[Good Design Award (Chicago)|Good Design Award]] from the Chicago Athenaeum, Museum of Architecture and Design in 2007.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.allbusiness.com/legal/banking-law-banking-finance-regulation/5328453-1.html |title=Acme United Corporation Announces Good DesignAward |publisher=allbusiness.com}} Retrieved on April 25, 2011.&lt;/ref&gt;

Early 2013, Clauss launched a family of titanium bonded non-stick putty knives. Its coating prevents the tools from rusting, which is a very common problem in wet environments, and it allows easier application of the putty.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/04/04/ct-acme-united-corp-idUSnBw8G7Mh8a+128+BSW20130404  |title=ScottsMiracle-Gro and Acme United Launch Innovative Lawn and Garden Tools |publisher=reuters.com}} Retrieved on May 18, 2012.&lt;/ref&gt;

More recently, Acme formed a partnership with The ScottsMiracle-Gro Company (NYSE: SMG) to market and sell two lines of lawn and gardening tools branded ‘Scotts’ and ‘Miracle-Gro’. The tools also carry the ‘powered by Clauss technology’ label.

The Miracle-Gro is a line of lawn and garden products such as pruners, snips, floral knives and spring assisted scissors suited for home gardeners. The Scotts line, on the other hand, aims at lawn care professionals and serious DIY’ers. It includes loppers, hedge shears, branch saws and grass and garden shears. 

The tools were officially launched in May of 2013 at the National Hardware Show, which is an annual housing after-market show that brings together manufacturers and resellers of all products used to remodel, repair, maintain and decorate the home and garden. 

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.acmeunited.com Acme United Corp. Company Website]
*[http://www.claussco.com Clauss Company Website]
*[http://www.jahenckels.com Zwilling J.A. Henckels website]
*[http://www.alcoind.com Alco Industries Inc. Company Website]
{{Acme United Corporation}}

[[Category:Knife manufacturing companies]]
[[Category:Scissors]]</text>
      <sha1>rkj5zj0dfhoi6b6nrdii6l2e8tktwvt</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Pruning shears</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>5396663</id>
    <revision>
      <id>612164903</id>
      <parentid>598910344</parentid>
      <timestamp>2014-06-09T04:04:03Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Plastikspork</username>
        <id>5075409</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* External links */ Split per TfD</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="3397">[[File:Secateur ouvert.jpg|thumb|Bypass secateurs]]

'''Pruning shears''', also called '''hand pruners''' (in American English), or '''secateurs''', are a type of [[scissors]] for use on plants.  They are strong enough to [[pruning|prune]] hard branches of [[trees]] and [[shrubs]], sometimes up to two centimetres thick.  They are used in [[gardening]], [[arboriculture]], [[farming]], [[flower arranging]], and [[nature conservation]], where fine-scale habitat management is required. 

[[Loppers]] are a larger, two-handed, long-handled version for branches thicker than pruning shears can cut.

==History==
Scissors only used for gardening work have existed since 1819, when the French aristocrat Antoine Francois Bertrand de Molleville was listed in &quot;Bon Jardinier&quot;, as the first inventor of secateurs. During the late 1890s, secateurs were sold all over Europe and the US. Nowadays every pro- and semiprofessional gardener, vintner and fruit farmer uses secateurs.

==Designs==
[[File:Pruning shears removableblade.JPG|thumb|left|200px|Professional pruning shears often have replaceable blades]]
There are three different blade designs for pruning shears: ''anvil'', ''bypass'' and ''parrot-beak''.  Anvil pruners have only one blade, which closes onto a flat surface. They tend to crush the stem, but remain reliable when they are slightly blunt. Anvil pruners are useful for cutting thick branches. Bypass pruners usually work exactly like a pair of scissors, with two blades &quot;passing by&quot; each other to make the cut.  At least one of the blades will be curved: a convex upper blade with either a concave or straight lower one.  Some bypass designs have only one blade, the lower jaw being broad (like an anvil) but passing the upper jaw.  Parrot-beak pruners consist of two concave passing blades, which trap the stem between them to make the cut.  These are suitable only for narrower stems.
&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book
 | last = Bird
 | first = Richard
 | year = 2002
 | title = Garden Answers: Pruning
 | publisher = Hamlyn
 | location = London
 | isbn = 0-600-61024-1
}}&lt;/ref&gt;

==Handle length==
[[File:Averruncator.png|thumb|200px|Fig.1 shows the handle and head of an averruncator. Fig. 2 shows the head in use.]]
Secateurs have short [[handle (grip)|handle]]s and are operated with one hand.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book
 | title = Oxford Dictionary of English
 | origyear = 1998
 | edition = 2nd edition (revised)
 | year = 2005
 | publisher = Oxford University Press
 | location = Oxford
 | isbn = 0-19-861314-8 }}&lt;/ref&gt;  A [[spring (device)|spring]] between the handles causes the jaws to open again after closing.  When not in use, the jaws may be held closed by a safety catch or by a loop holding the handles together.  Some types are designed for right-handed or left-handed use only, and some incorporate a rotating handle to reduce [[friction]] and minimize hand stress during repetitive use.  There are also longer versions called telescopic pruners, which are adjustable for long-reach and operate by means of a rod system inside of a telescoping pole between the handles and the blades.  An early version of these was known as an [[averruncator]].

==See also==
*[[Garden tool]]

==References==
&lt;references/&gt;

== External links ==
* {{commons category-inline|Secateurs}}

{{Garden tools}}

[[Category:Gardening tools]]
[[Category:Habitat management equipment and methods]]
[[Category:Scissors]]</text>
      <sha1>9uojumjb4cxny8qaf30z41xy93jsl88</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Surgical scissors</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>30040768</id>
    <revision>
      <id>566593010</id>
      <parentid>566582074</parentid>
      <timestamp>2013-07-31T16:16:20Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Saltanat ebli</username>
        <id>17096007</id>
      </contributor>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="1902">{{unreferenced|date=December 2010}}
'''Surgical scissors''' are [[surgical instrument]]s usually used for cutting. They include [[bandage scissors]], [[dissecting scissors]], [[iris scissors]], [[operating scissors]], [[stitch scissors]], [[tenotomy scissors]], [[Metzenbaum scissors]], [[plastic surgery scissors]], and [[Mayo scissors]]. Surgical scissors are usually made of very hard [[stainless steel]] for ongoing toughness. Some scissors have [[tungsten carbide]] reinforcements along their cutting edges. The [[hardness]] of this material allows the manufacturers to create sharper edges, which allows for easier and smoother cuts and keeps the scissors sharp for longer.

==Types==
There are two types of scissors used in surgeries. 
* Ring scissors look much like standard utility scissors with two finger loops.
* Spring scissors are small scissors used mostly in [[eye surgery]] or [[microsurgery]]. The handles end in flat springs connected with a pivot joint. The cutting action is achieved by pressing the handles together. As the pressure is released, the spring action opens the jaws.

Scissors are available in various configurations like
* Blunt/blunt blades
* Blunt/sharp blades
* Sharp/sharp blades

== Material ==
Usually material of surgical scissor are [[Surgical stainless steel|stainless steel]], zirconia ceramic, nitinol and titanium.
==Gallery==
&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Metzenbaum scissors 04.jpg| [[Metzenbaum scissors]] 
File:Surgical scissors 07.JPG |Mayo Scissors
File:Bandage Scissors.JPG |Bandage Scissors
&lt;/gallery&gt;
==See also==
{{commons category}}
*[[Trauma shears]]
*[[Bandage scissors]]
*[[Hemostat]], a surgical clamp resembling scissors
*[[Needle holder]], an instrument resembling scissors used to hold a suturing needle

== References ==
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Surgical scissors| ]]
[[Category:Scissors]]
[[Category:Surgical instruments]]

{{medical-equipment-stub}}</text>
      <sha1>bonihadaz7s5lrve0vosgf2ghf7nu0j</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Pinking shears</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>233458</id>
    <revision>
      <id>598230374</id>
      <parentid>598092419</parentid>
      <timestamp>2014-03-05T08:24:16Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>BG19bot</username>
        <id>14508071</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>/* Patents */[[WP:CHECKWIKI]] error fix for #61.  Punctuation goes before References. Do [[Wikipedia:GENFIXES|general fixes]] if a problem exists. - using [[Project:AWB|AWB]] (9957)</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="4376">{{Refimprove|date=September 2012}}
[[Image:Zackenschere.jpg|thumb|200px|Pinking shears]]
'''Pinking shears''' are [[scissors]], the blades of which are sawtoothed instead of straight.  They leave a [[zigzag]] pattern instead of a straight edge.

Pinking shears have a utilitarian function for cutting [[woven]] [[cloth]]. Cloth edges that are unfinished will easily fray, the weave becoming undone and threads pulling out easily. The sawtooth pattern does not prevent the fraying but limits the length of the frayed thread and thus minimizes damage.

==Other applications==
These scissors can also be used for decorative cuts and a number of patterns (arches, sawtooth of different aspect ratios, or asymmetric teeth) are available.  True dressmaker's pinking shears, however, should not be used for paper decoration because paper dulls the cutting edge.

==Etymology==
The cut produced by pinking shears may have given its name to (or be derived from) the plant name [[Pink (flower)|pink]], a [[flowering plant]] in the genus ''[[Dianthus]]'' (commonly called a carnation). The colour [[pink]] may have been named after these flowers, although the origins of the name are not definitively known. As the carnation has scalloped, or &quot;pinked&quot;, edges to its [[petals]], pinking shears can be thought to produce an edge similar to the flower{{citation needed|date=March 2014}}.

The word &quot;[[pink]]&quot; can be used as a verb dating back to 1300 meaning &quot;pierce, stab, make holes in&quot;.  The French word ''piquer'' and Spanish word ''picar'' are derived from the Latin ''pungere'' meaning &quot;to pierce, prick&quot; and related to &quot;[[pungent]]&quot;{{citation needed|date=March 2014}}.

==Patents==
Louise Austin of [[Whatcom County, Washington|Whatcom, Washington]], received {{US patent|489,406}} on January 3, 1893, for &quot;pinking scissors.&quot; The patent describes how &quot;pinking scissors&quot; are superior to the existing tools at the time, &quot;pinking irons&quot; and &quot;pinking cutters.&quot;   The operation of the shears are described as &quot;pinking&quot; or &quot;scalloping.&quot;  There are references to &quot;cut ornamental openings in the body portion of fabrics,&quot; but no references to the more utilitarian function of preventing fraying. One of the primary early uses of pinking shears was the formation of decorative edging for patchwork quilting squares.

Samuel Briskman, of Brooklyn, received {{US patent|1959190}}, for a method of manufacturing pinking shears, and {{US patent|1965443}} and {{US patent|1970408}}, describing the shears themselves, in 1934. He formed the Pinking Shears Corporation and set up a factory at 102 Prince Street in Manhattan. His firm milled the teeth into the blades. Wiss made the actual shears and had the exclusive sales in the USA and through their agents abroad. Briskman was also entitled to sell abroad under the name of Pinking Shears Corp. through his agents. He had one son, Artie, who worked with him. Sales fell off after a change in the type of fabric that was popular. Briskman died in February 1967, and was known as an inventor and philanthropist at that time.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://spiderbites.nytimes.com/pay_1967/articles_1967_02_00002.html |title=Pay Articles from February 1967 Part 3 - Site Map - The New York Times |publisher=Spiderbites.nytimes.com |date= |accessdate=2012-09-17}}&lt;/ref&gt;  Norman Wiss, Sr. was the one who pushed for and who managed the agreement with Briskman.

Benjamin Luscalzo, of [[Chicago]], [[Illinois]], received {{US patent|2600036}} on June 10, 1952, for his improvements to pinking shears. He provided an adjustable tension means connected to one of the blades or jaws of the shears which kept the teeth in efficient cutting relationship so that the cutting plane is always perpendicular to the pivotal axis.  In other words, Benjamin Luscalzo brought traditional scissors and the pinking blade together to create what we know today as pinking shears.

Method of Making Pinking Shears (Model A) {{US patent|1,959,190}}, Filed March 17, 1932; Issued May 15, 1934

Pinking Shears (Model A) {{US patent|1,965,443}}, Filed March 17, 1932; Issued July 3, 1934

Pinking Shears (Model C) {{US patent|1,970,408}}, Filed September 19, 1931; Issued August 14, 1934

The Perfect Pinker {{US patent|2174222}} Metropolitan Cutting Co. Crane Brand, A Florian Product

==References==
{{Reflist}}

{{sewing}}

[[Category:Scissors]]
[[Category:Sewing equipment]]</text>
      <sha1>qexrlzi9vsy1nv2hr7avo4pgkprp8dj</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Thinning scissors</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>36321902</id>
    <revision>
      <id>567415054</id>
      <parentid>564326065</parentid>
      <timestamp>2013-08-06T16:01:23Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Pol098</username>
        <id>169132</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>wording</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="563">{{unreferenced|date=July 2012}}
[[File:Modellierschere.jpg|thumb|Blades of a pair of thinning scissors]]
'''Thinning scissors''', '''thinning shears''',  '''texturizing shears''' or '''chunking shears''' are special scissors with which [[hairdresser]]s and [[barber]]s reduce hair thickness, to create special [[texturizing]] effects or to blend [[layered hair]]. Thinning scissors have a pair of pivoted blades in the same way as normal [[scissors]], but one or both blades have teeth on the edge like a [[comb]].

[[Category:Hairdressing]]
[[Category:Scissors]]</text>
      <sha1>48z21kdzg591k7krok1436gxwtghu4m</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Category:Surgical scissors</title>
    <ns>14</ns>
    <id>37113763</id>
    <revision>
      <id>589003128</id>
      <parentid>546406926</parentid>
      <timestamp>2014-01-03T17:21:29Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>BotMultichill</username>
        <id>4080734</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Adding Commons category link to [[:Commons:Category:Surgical scissors|category with the same name]]</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="108">{{Commons category|Surgical scissors}}
{{Cat main}}

[[Category:Scissors]]
[[Category:Surgical instruments]]</text>
      <sha1>50ouq9ghdhhm0l60mm19y9he377cprs</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Meerut scissors</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>38257492</id>
    <revision>
      <id>593982477</id>
      <parentid>546217374</parentid>
      <timestamp>2014-02-05T01:51:22Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ansh666</username>
        <id>5305553</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>Added {{[[Template:notability|notability]]}} and {{[[Template:ref improve|ref improve]]}} tags to article ([[WP:TW|Twinkle]])</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="2375">{{notability|date=February 2014}}
{{ref improve|date=February 2014}}
'''Meerut Scissors''' is a pair of scissors made of recycled metal scrap by the microlevel industrial units run by a community in [[Meerut]], North [[India]]. The community has been making the product for more than three centuries.&lt;ref name=&quot;HinduNews&quot;&gt;[http://www.thehindu.com/todays-paper/tp-national/meerut-scissors-make-the-cut-for-gi-tag/article4292580.ece Meerut scissors make the cut for GI tag]&lt;/ref&gt;

==Recycling from waste==
Meerut Scissors are particularly used for garment making and other domestic uses. All parts of the scissors are pre-used in some other form.&lt;ref name=&quot;HinduNews&quot; /&gt; For e.g. the blades are made from recycled carbon steel sourced  from scrap metal salvaged out of old railway rolling stocks,automobiles etc. The handles made of alloys, plastics etc. are prepared from other wastes such as old utensils. The first such scissors were made by Asli Akhun some 360 years ago.&lt;ref name=&quot;HinduNews&quot; /&gt; Unlike most other scissors, these scissors can be repaired and reused many a times. An idiom popular around Meerut refers to the quality and re-usability of these instruments as a testimony :''Dada le, potaa barpe'' (&quot;bought by the grandfather, (still) used by the grandson&quot;).&lt;ref name=&quot;HinduNews&quot; /&gt;

==Geographic Indication Tag==
In January 2013, the product was recognized to qualify for its own [[Geographical Indication]]. It was the 164th among a list of such specially tagged commodity items in India.&lt;ref name=&quot;HinduNews&quot; /&gt;
Until now, these scissors used to be produce din a variety of sizes ranging from six inches to 14 inches. They also had different price ranges from 20 Rupees to 500 Rupees. However, with the GI tags, the producers are encouraged to come up with some standard sizes and price levels.&lt;ref name=&quot;HinduNews&quot; /&gt;

The industry is well established around Meerut with 250 small-scale scissors-making units, employing 70,000 people directly and indirectly.&lt;ref name=&quot;HinduNews&quot; /&gt; While men makes the scissors, women add their share of the efforts by performing tasks that require handwork and pack the products. Even when the market is confined to domestic consumption, makers find it tough to meet the demand.&lt;ref name=&quot;HinduNews&quot; /&gt;

==References==
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Scissors]]
[[Category:Meerut]]
[[Category:Geographical Indications in India]]</text>
      <sha1>61dnuv8qlzncy7b2tzxa0qt7864d97n</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
  <page>
    <title>Scissors</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>254938</id>
    <revision>
      <id>616846545</id>
      <parentid>616265253</parentid>
      <timestamp>2014-07-14T00:13:06Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <ip>72.130.58.85</ip>
      </contributor>
      <comment>rm vandalism</comment>
      <text xml:space="preserve" bytes="19937">{{other uses}}
{{refimprove|date=September 2009}}
[[Image:A pair of scissors.jpg|thumb|A pair of black &amp; red scissors]]
[[Image:Skalm 2.JPG|thumb|A pair of standard, large scissors]]
'''Scissors''' are hand-operated shearing instruments. They consist of a pair of [[metal]] [[blade]]s pivoted so that the sharpened edges slide against each other when the handles (bows) opposite to the pivot are closed. Scissors are used for cutting various thin materials, such as [[paper]], [[Paperboard|cardboard]], [[metal leaf|metal foil]], thin [[plastic]], [[cloth]], [[rope]], and [[wire]]. Scissors can also be used to cut [[hair]]. Hair cutting scissors have a specific blade angle ideal for cutting hair. Using the incorrect scissors to cut hair will result in increased damage and or split ends by breaking the hair. [[Food]] scissors, also known as kitchen scissors, are for cutting and trimming foods such as meats. Hair cutting scissors and [[Kitchen shears|shears]] are functionally equivalent, but the larger implements tend to be called [[Kitchen shears|shears]].

A large variety of scissors and shears exist for different specialized purposes.

Modern scissors are normally designed [[ergonomically]] with composite [[thermoplastic]] and [[rubber]]  [[handle (grip)|handle]]s which enable the user to exert either a power grip or a precision grip.

==Terminology==
The noun  &quot;scissors&quot; is treated as a [[Plurale tantum|plural noun]], and therefore takes a plural verb (&quot;these scissors are&quot;). Alternatively, it is also referred to as &quot;a pair of scissors&quot;. In American English, &quot;a pair&quot; is singular and therefore takes a singular verb (&quot;this pair of scissors is&quot;). In other forms of English, &quot;a pair&quot; does not take the singular (so simply &quot;these scissors are&quot;).
The word '''shears''' is used to describe similar instruments that are larger in size and for heavier cutting. Opinions vary geographically as to the size at which 'scissors' become 'shears', but this is often at between six to eight inches (about 15 to 20 cm) in length.

==History==
[[Image:Scissors turkey.jpg|thumb|Scissors from the 2nd century [[Asia Minor]]]]

It is most likely that scissors were invented around 1500 BC in [[ancient Egypt]].&lt;ref&gt;[http://inventors.about.com/library/inventors/blscissors.htm Who Invented Scissors&lt;!-- Bot generated title --&gt;]&lt;/ref&gt; The earliest known scissors appeared in [[Mesopotamia]] 3,000 to 4,000 years ago. These were of the 'spring scissor' type comprising two [[bronze]] blades connected at the handles by a thin, flexible strip of curved bronze which served to hold the blades in alignment, to allow them to be squeezed together, and to pull them apart when released.

Spring scissors continued to be used in Europe until the 16th century.  However, pivoted scissors of bronze or [[iron]], in which the blades were pivoted at a point between the tips and the handles, the direct ancestor of modern scissors, were invented by the [[Roman Empire|Romans]] around AD100.&lt;ref&gt;[http://www.enchantedlearning.com/inventors/italy.shtml Zoom Inventors and Inventions]&lt;/ref&gt;  They entered common use not only in ancient Rome, but also in [[China]], [[Japan]], and [[Korea]], and the idea is still used in almost all modern scissors.

===Early manufacture===
During the [[Middle Ages]] and [[Renaissance]], spring scissors were made by heating a bar of iron or steel, then flattening and shaping its ends into blades on an anvil. The center of the bar was heated, bent to form the spring, then cooled and reheated to make it flexible.

William Whiteley &amp; Sons (Sheffield) Ltd. was manufacturing scissors by 1760, although it is believed the business began trading even earlier. The first trade-mark, 332, was granted in 1791.{{Citation needed|date=February 2011}}

Pivoted scissors were not manufactured in large numbers until 1761, when [[Robert Hinchliffe]] produced the first pair of modern-day scissors made of hardened and polished cast steel. He lived in [[Cheney Square]], [[London]] and was reputed to be the first person who put out a signboard proclaiming himself &quot;fine scissor manufacturer&quot;.&lt;ref&gt;[http://freepages.history.rootsweb.com/~exy1/fh_material/18C_sheffield/ch4.txt REMINISCENCES OP SHEFFIELD]{{dead link|date=June 2012}}&lt;/ref&gt;

During the 19th century, scissors were hand-forged with elaborately decorated handles. They were made by hammering steel on indented surfaces known as bosses to form the blades. The rings in the handles, known as bows, were made by punching a hole in the steel and enlarging it with the pointed end of an anvil.

In 1649, in [[Sweden|Swedish]]-ruled [[Finland]], an ironworks was founded in the village of [[Fiskars, Finland|Fiskars]] between [[Helsinki]] and [[Turku]]. In 1830, a new owner started the first cutlery works in Finland, making, among other items, scissors with the [[Fiskars]] trademark. In 1967, Fiskars Corporation introduced new methods to scissors manufacturing.&lt;ref&gt;[http://www.fiskars.fi/pdf/Fiskars_history_eng.pdf ]{{dead link|date=February 2012}}&lt;/ref&gt;

==Description and operation==


A pair of scissors consists of two pivoted blades. In lower-quality scissors the cutting edges are not particularly sharp; it is primarily the [[Shearing (physics)|shearing]] action between the two blades that cuts the material. In high-quality scissors the blades can be both extremely sharp, and tension sprung - to increase the cutting and shearing tension only at the exact point where the blades meet. The hand movement (pushing with the thumb, pulling with the fingers in right handed use) can add to this tension. An ideal example is in high-quality tailor's scissors or shears, which need to be able to perfectly cut (and not simply tear apart) delicate cloths such as chiffon and silk.

[[Child]]ren's scissors are usually not particularly sharp, and the tips of the blades are often blunted or 'rounded' for safety.

Mechanically, scissors are a first-class double-[[lever]] with the pivot acting as the [[wikt:fulcrum|fulcrum]]. For cutting thick or heavy material, the [[mechanical advantage]] of a lever can be exploited by placing the material to be cut as close to the fulcrum as possible. For example, if the applied force (at the handles) is twice as far away from the fulcrum as the cutting location (i.e., the point of contact between the blades), the force at the cutting location is twice that of the applied force at the handles. Scissors cut material by applying a local [[shear stress]] at the cutting location which exceeds the material's [[shear strength]].

Some scissors have an appendage, called a finger brace or finger tang, below the index finger hole for the middle finger to rest on to provide for better control and more power in precision cutting. A finger tang can be found on many quality scissors (including inexpensive ones) and especially on scissors for cutting hair (see hair scissors pictured below).  In hair cutting, some claim the ring finger is inserted where some place their index finger, and the little finger rests on the finger tang.

For people who do not have the use of their hands, there are specially designed foot operated scissors. Some quadriplegics can use a motorized mouth-operated style of scissor.

==Left-handed scissors==
[[Image:2scissors-clean.jpg|thumb|Left-handed (left) and right-handed (right) scissors]]
Most scissors are best-suited for use with the right hand, but ''left-handed'' scissors are designed for use with the left hand. Because scissors have overlapping blades, they are not symmetric. This asymmetry is true regardless of the orientation and shape of the handles: the blade that is on top always forms the same diagonal regardless of orientation. Human hands are also asymmetric, and when closing, the thumb and fingers do not close vertically, but have a lateral component to the motion.  Specifically, the thumb pushes out from the palm and the fingers pull inwards. For right-handed scissors held in the right hand, the thumb blade is closer to the user's body, so that the natural tendency of the right hand is to force the cutting blades together.  Conversely, if right-handed scissors are held in the left hand, the natural tendency of the left hand would be to force the cutting blades laterally apart. Furthermore, with right-handed scissors held by the right-hand, the shearing edge is visible, but when used with the left hand, the cutting edge of the scissors is behind the top blade, and one cannot see what is being cut.

Some scissors are marketed as [[ambidextrous]]. These have symmetric handles so there is no distinction between the thumb and finger handles, and have very strong pivots so that the blades simply rotate and do not have any lateral give. However, most &quot;ambidextrous&quot; scissors are in fact still right-handed in that the upper blade is on the right, and hence is on the outside when held in the right hand. Even if they successfully cut, the blade orientation will block the view of the cutting line for a left-handed person. True ambidextrous scissors are possible if the blades are double-edged and one handle is swung all the way around (to almost 360 [[Degree (angle)|degrees]]) so that the back of the blades become the new cutting edges. Patents ({{US patent|3978584}}) have been awarded for true ambidextrous scissors.

==Specialized scissors==
Among specialized scissors and shears used for different purposes are:

===Agriculture and animal husbandry===
* [[Hedge trimmer]]s, for trimming [[hedge (barrier)|hedges]]
* [[Grass shears]], for trimming [[grass]]
*[[Averruncator]]s, for trimming high branches
*[[Pruning shears]] or secateurs, for trimming small [[branch]]es
*[[Loppers]], for cutting through large [[branch]]es
* [[Sheep shearing#Blade shears|Blade shears]], for cutting an animal's fleece to make [[wool]]
&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Taille haie.jpg|Hedge trimmers
File:Gardena-Grasschere klassisch.jpg|Grass shears
File:Averruncator.png|Averruncators
File:Secateur ouvert.jpg|Pruning shears
File:Astschere.jpg|Loppers
File:BladeShears.jpg|Blade shears
&lt;/gallery&gt;

===Food and drug===
* Kitchen scissors or kitchen shears, for food preparation, but often used for a variety of other purposes. In modern times, kitchen scissors are usually made from stainless steel for food hygiene and oxidization-resistance reasons. They often have kitchen functionality (other than cutting) incorporated, such as bottle-cap and bottle-openers built into the handles.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.ernestwright.co.uk/catalogue/browse.aspx?productId=218&amp;breadcrumb=13_52 |title=Ernest Wright and Son Ltd Scissors : Kitchen Scissors &gt; Kitchen Scissors Traditional Design 7 inch |publisher=Ernestwright.co.uk |date= |accessdate=2012-02-28}}&lt;/ref&gt;
* Poultry shears, to cut cooked [[poultry]]
* [[Cigar cutter]], specialized scissors with concave blade edges to cut cigars

&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Kitchen-Scissors.jpg|Kitchen scissors
File:Cigar cutter.JPG|Cigar cutter
&lt;/gallery&gt;

===Grooming===
* [[Hair clipper]]s, for cutting hair by [[barber]]s, [[hairdresser]]s, and [[Dog grooming|pet groomers]]
** [[Thinning scissors]], for thinning thick hair to avoid a bushy look
* Nail scissors, for cutting [[fingernail|finger-]] and [[toenail]]s
* Moustache scissors, for trimming [[moustache]]s
&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Modellierschere.jpg|The blades of thinning scissors
File:Hair Cutting Scissors.jpg|Hair scissors
File:Nagelschere.jpg|Nail scissors
File:Mustache Scissors.jpg|Moustache scissors
&lt;/gallery&gt;

===Metalwork===
*[[Snips]], for cutting through [[sheet metal]].
**Tin, or tinner, snips
**Compound action snips
**Pipe and duct snips
*[[Hydraulic rescue tools|Hydraulic cutters]], for cutting heavy sheet metal, often in [[traffic collisions]]. Sometimes referred to by the [[genericized trademark]] &quot;Jaws of Life&quot;.
*[[Throatless shear]]s, for cutting complex shapes in sheet metal
&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Combination snips.png|Snips
File:Extrication cutter 1.jpg|Hydraulic cutters
File:ThroatlessShear.jpg|Throatless sheers
&lt;/gallery&gt;

===Medical===
*[[Trauma shears]], or &quot;tuff cuts&quot;, for use in emergency medical response and rescue. The rounded tips are designed to slide across human flesh without harm allowing quick removal of clothing
*Dissection scissors, for cutting flesh in [[dissection]]
*[[Surgical scissors]], for cutting flesh in [[surgery]]
**[[Iris scissors]], for [[ophthalmic surgery]]
**[[Metzenbaum scissors]], for delicate surgery
**[[Tenotomy scissors]], for delicate surgery
**[[Mayo scissors]], often for cutting [[fascia]]
*[[Bandage scissors]], for cutting bandages

&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Aa trauma shears.jpg|Trauma shears
File:Surgical instruments3.JPG|Surgical or dissecting scissors
&lt;/gallery&gt;

===Ceremonial===
*[[Ceremonial scissors]], for [[Ribbon-cutting ceremony|ceremonial ribbon-cutting events]]&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.ernestwright.co.uk/catalogue/browse.aspx?productId=204&amp;breadcrumb=13_49 |title=Ernest Wright and Son Ltd Scissors : Ceremonial, Presentation &amp; Gift &gt; Gold Ribbon Cutting Ceremonial Scissors |publisher=Ernestwright.co.uk |date= |accessdate=2012-02-28}}&lt;/ref&gt;

&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Joshua Kent, with the help of Col. Jay Silveria cut the ribbon and Carlos Mencia Kid Rock and Jessie James cut the ribbon to open new fitness stations at RAF Lakenheath.jpg|Ceremonial scissors
&lt;/gallery&gt;

===Sewing and clothes-making===
[[File:Zackenschere.jpg|thumb|right|Pinking shears]]
* [[Pinking shears]], for cutting cloth and producing a serrated edge so that the fabric does not fray.
* Sewing Chatelaine Scissors. [[Chatelaine (chain)|Chatelaine]] is a French term meaning &quot;mistress of a castle, chateau or stately home&quot;, and dates back to the Middle Ages.  It refers to an ornamental clasp or hook from which chains were hung from the waist,  holding perhaps,  a purse, watch, keys, scissors or thimble case.  The sewing chatelaine became a popular ornamental appendage worn by Victorian ladies at their waist,  but disappeared when fashion changed and skirts were no longer full and long. Sewing chatelaines are now produced and worn as pendants around the neck.

==Scissors gallery==
&lt;gallery&gt;
Image:Scissors china.jpg|Scissors from the Chinese [[Tang dynasty]] (618–907)
Image:Iron scissors, E Han.JPG|A pair of iron scissors dating from the [[Han Dynasty]]
Image:Skalm 2.JPG|Fiskars scissors 1967
File:Scissors2.JPG|General purpose scissors
Image:Schere Gr 99.jpg|A pair of shears
&lt;/gallery&gt;

==Culture==
Due to their ubiquity across cultures and classes, scissors have numerous representations across world culture.

===Art===
Numerous forms of art worldwide enlist scissors as a tool/material with which to accomplish the art; in this section, we will be looking at cases where scissors appear in or are represented by the [[commons:Category:Scissors in art|final art product]].

===Film===
*''[[Edward Scissorhands]]'' is a 1990 film starring [[Johnny Depp]] as a young man who has hands made of multiple pairs of scissors.
*''[[Running with Scissors (film)|Running with Scissors]]'' is a 2006 film based on the memoir of the same title.

===Games===
The game [[Rock-paper-scissors|Rock-Paper-Scissors]] involves two or more players making shapes with their hands to determine the outcome of the game. One of the three shapes, 'scissors', is made by extending the index and middle fingers to mimic the shape of most scissors.

===Literature===
[[Augusten Burroughs]]' 2002 [[memoir]] ''[[Running with Scissors (memoir)|Running with Scissors]]'' spent eight weeks on the [[New York Times Best Seller List|''New York Times'' best seller list]]. The book was later adapted into a film.

===Music===
*''[[Running with Scissors (album)|Running with Scissors]]'' is the title of a 1999 album by [[&quot;Weird Al&quot; Yankovic]].
*The song &quot;The Tailor Shop on Enbizaka (円尾坂の仕立屋 ''Enbizaka no Shitateya'')&quot; from [[Vocaloid]] producer Akuno-P tells a story about a tailor that kills a man, his wife and their two daughters using her Sewing Scissors.
*The [[XTC]] song &quot;Scissor Man&quot;, later covered by [[Primus (band)|Primus]].

*Save your Scissors - song by City and Colour.

===Sport===
The term 'scissor kick' may be found in several sports, including:
*[[Scissor kick (strike)]], a generic martial arts term for any of a number of moves that may resemble the appearance or action of a pair of scissors.
*[[Bicycle kick]]s in [[association football|football]] are sometimes known as 'scissor kicks'.
*[[Human swimming|Swimming]] strokes including the [[sidestroke]] incorporate a leg movement often known as a 'scissor kick'.

===Superstition===
Scissors have a widespread place in cultural superstitions. In many cases, the specifics of the superstition may be specific to a given country, region, tribe, religion or even situation.
*Africa
**In parts of North [[Africa]], it was held that scissors could be used to [[curse]] a bridegroom. When the bridegroom was on horseback, the person enacting the curse would stand behind him with the scissors open and call his name. If the bridegroom answered to his name being called, the scissors would then be snapped shut and the bridegroom would be unable to consummate his marriage with his bride.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite book|url=http://books.google.com/books?id=Ht_02x-2JksC&amp;lpg=PA213&amp;ots=gAC9ciQGbw&amp;dq=scissors%20superstitions&amp;pg=PA213#v=onepage&amp;q=scissors%20superstitions&amp;f=false |title=Encyclopedia of Superstitions 1949 - Edwin Radford, Mona A. Radford - Google Boeken |publisher=Books.google.com |date= |accessdate=2012-02-28}}&lt;/ref&gt;
*Asia
**In Pakistan, some believe that scissors should never be idly opened and closed without purpose. This is believed to cause bad luck.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|author=DJPianz |url=http://worldsuperstitions.blogspot.com/2011/05/pakistan-scissors.html |title=Superstitions around the world: Pakistan - Scissors |publisher=Worldsuperstitions.blogspot.com |date=2011-05-04 |accessdate=2012-02-28}}&lt;/ref&gt;
*North America
**United States
***In [[New Orleans]], some believed that putting an open pair of scissors underneath your [[pillow]] at night was a sound method for sleeping well, even if one might be cursed.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.sacred-texts.com/afr/hearn/nos.htm |title=NEW ORLEANS SUPERSTITIONS (1886) by Lafcadio Hearn |publisher=Sacred-texts.com |date= |accessdate=2012-02-28}}&lt;/ref&gt;
*Eastern Europe
**It is believed in some Eastern European countries that leaving scissors open causes fights and disagreement within a household.
*China
**It is believed in China that giving scissors to a friend or loved ones is to be cutting ties with them.

===Science===
Scissors have been used in the sciences for various purposes, including descriptions of animals or natural features.

===Nature===
Animals named after scissors include:
*Birds
**The [[Scissor-tailed Flycatcher]] of North and Central America.
**The [[Scissor-tailed Hummingbird]]
**The [[Scissor-tailed Kite]], a bird that is widespread throughout Africa.
**The [[Scissor-tailed Nightjar]] of [[South America]].
*Fish
**The [[Scissor-tail rasbora]], a species of fish that is commonly used for freshwater aquariums.&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|author=Aquaticcommunity |url=http://www.aquaticcommunity.com/fish/scissortail.php |title=Scissortail - Rasbora trilineata |publisher=Aquaticcommunity.com |date= |accessdate=2012-02-28}}&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref&gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.fishlore.com/profile-scissortail.htm |title=Scissor Tail Rasbora - Rasbora trilineata |publisher=Fishlore.com |date= |accessdate=2012-02-28}}&lt;/ref&gt;

==See also==
*[[Hemostat]] resembles a pair of scissors, but is used as a clamp in [[surgery]] and does not cut at all.
*[[Nipper (tool)|Nippers]] cut small pieces out of [[tile]].
*[[Pliers]] used for holding and [[crimp connection|crimping]] metal or wire.

==References==
{{Commons category|Scissors}}
{{reflist}}

{{Cutting and abrasive tools}}
{{crochet}}
{{embroidery}}
{{knitting}}
{{sewing}}

[[Category:Scissors| ]]
[[Category:Sewing equipment]]
[[Category:Embroidery equipment]]</text>
      <sha1>s7ex8i7szncky3o6lvkyaj1v679ow5g</sha1>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
